Phyllis and Weldon Heald papers, 1872-1993 (bulk 1955-1993)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Phyllis and Weldon Heald papers, 1872-1993 (bulk 1955-1993)
MS 359
Phyllis and Weldon Heald
Most of the collection consists of manuscripts of various works by Phyllis and Weldon Heald. Also within the collection are articles, clippings, and miscellaneous materials about the Healds and other topics. The majority of the photographs were taken by the Healds during their travels throughout the Southwest.
1.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Phyllis and Weldon Heald were free-lance writers who relocated to southeast Arizona from the northeast. They owned the Flying H Ranch in the Huachuca Mountains, and the Painted Canyon Ranch in the Chiricahua Mountains before settling down to write full-time in Tucson. They wrote books, articles, short stories, poems, plays and screenplays. Much of their writing was on the flora and fauna of the Southwest as well as historical sites in Arizona. Before his career as a writer, artist and photographer, Weldon worked as an architect. He wrote several books including, "Sky Island," and "The Arizona Scenic Guide." Phyllis began her career as a playwright and she continued to write plays with her husband. The Healds taught writing workshops at the Southwest Writers Conference in Flagstaff. Later in her career, Phyllis was a writing consultant for writers.
Organization
This collection is organized into five series
Series I: Manuscripts, 1958-1991
Series II: Articles and Clippings, 1952-1993
Series III: Certificates and Awards, 1972-1980
Series IV: Miscellaneous, 1955-1992
Series V: Photographs, ca 1872-1993
Scope and Content Note
Most of the collection consists of manuscripts of various works by Phyllis and Weldon Heald. Also within the collection are articles, clippings, and miscellaneous materials about the Healds and other topics. The majority of the photographs were taken by the Healds during their travels throughout the Southwest. Other images were made by Stephan Blake, Manley photography, the Las Vegas News Bureau, or are reproductions from various historical societies. The photographs are of outdoor scenes taken throughout the Southwest.
Access Terms
Heald, Phyllis
Heald, Weldon
Wildlife refuges--Arizona
Manuscripts, American
Natural history--Arizona
Southwest, New--Description and travel
Arizona--Description and travel
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts 1958-1991
  - Subseries: Articles and Short Stories
    - Articles and short stories: A, 1970, 1988, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Articles and short stories: B, 1972, 1991, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Articles and short stories: C, 1980s, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Articles and short stories: D, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Articles and short stories: E, 1967, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Articles and short stories: F, 1989, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Articles and short stories: G, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Articles and short stories: H, 1966, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Articles and short stories: I, 1967, 1990s, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Articles and short stories: J, 1959, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Articles and short stories: L, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Articles and short stories: M, 1990s, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Articles and short stories: O, 1966, 1989, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Articles and short stories: P, 1980s, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Articles and short stories: R, 1987, 1990, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Articles and short stories: S, 1966, 1983, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Articles and short stories: T, 1958, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Articles and short stories: U, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Articles and short stories: W-Y 1983,1990, Unknown dates (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Subseries: Books
    - Big Bird, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Heaven is Too Far, Unknown date (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Once Upon a Rainy Day, Unknown date (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Once Upon a Rainy Day, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Subseries: Poems
    - A-W, 1989, Unknown dates (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subseries: Plays
    - Tumble Weeds, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Woman from the North, Unknown date (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - The Woman Who Didn't, Unknown date (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Women in His Life, 1936? (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - White Fences, 1940s (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Subseries: Screenplays
    - Blueberry Pie and Coffee, Unknown date (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Good Tactics, Unknown date (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - The Mikado takes a Boo! Unknown date (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Series II: Articles and Clippings 1952-1993, Unknown dates
  - A-I, 1950-1990s (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - L-O, 1950-1960s, Unknown dates (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - R-W, 1960s, Unknown dates (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Series III: Certificates and Awards 1972-1980
  - Certificates and Awards, 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous 1955-1992, Unknown dates
  - Miscellaneous: Biographical and reference materials, 1955-1992, Unknown dates (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Series V: Photographs ca.1872-1993
  - Phyllis and Weldon Heald, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - People including authors Francis P. Farquhar and C.P. Snow, 1930-1971 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Heald home: Painted Canyon Ranch. Photographs by Stephen Blake, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Arizona places: Mission in the Sun, Parker Canyon Lake, Coronado National Memorial, Mt. Graham, Huachuca Mtns., Weaver's Needle, Montezuma Castle, Post Hospital at old Ft. Lowell, All Creed's Chapel, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Tombstone, AZ ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - San Xavier del Bac, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Other states: California, Washington, New Mexico, Nevada and Utah, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Unidentified places, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Animals, ca. 1940-50s (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Arizona plants, ca. 1950s (Box 4, Folder 46)